export const gst111Questions = [
  // Regular questions
  {
    question:
      "The …………… is otherwise known as the sender or source of the message.",
    options: ["stimulus", "channel", "human", "encoder"],
    answer: "encoder",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When the sender of a message uses words that are too difficult for the receiver to understand, this is called ………… noise.",
    options: ["Linguistic", "semantic", "grammatical", "Channel"],
    answer: "semantic",
  },
  {
    question: "One of the following is not a type of communication.",
    options: ["verbal", "chronemics", "non-verbal", "imagination"],
    answer: "imagination",
  },
  {
    question: "One of the following is not a faulty reading habit.",
    options: ["sub-vocalisation", "regression", "fatigue", "head movement"],
    answer: "fatigue",
  },
  {
    question:
      "………… is reading at the fastest speed possible to extract relevant/main ideas.",
    options: ["skimming", "scanning", "intensive reading", "extensive reading"],
    answer: "skimming",
  },
  {
    question: "She had prayed before they came (What tense is this?)",
    options: [
      "present perfect",
      "past perfect",
      "simple past",
      "present continuous",
    ],
    answer: "past perfect",
  },
  {
    question: "It rained heavily today (What tense is this?)",
    options: [
      "present perfect",
      "past perfect",
      "simple past",
      "past continuous",
    ],
    answer: "simple past",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The pattern of organisational communication in which information flows across staff, workers, departments and units in an establishment is _______",
    options: [
      "Horizontal communication",
      "Downward vertical communication",
      "Upward vertical communication",
      "Quasi-vertical communication",
    ],
    answer: "Horizontal communication",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which are odd nouns in the following numbers 09 and 15: crowd, team, friendship, herd?",
    options: ["crowd", "team", "friendship", "herd"],
    answer: "friendship",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following sentences is faulty?",
    options: [
      "The three girls love one another",
      "The man is a cheat",
      "John is a very trickish man",
      "The news was broadcast last night",
    ],
    answer: "John is a very trickish man",
  },
  {
    question:
      "------------- essay seeks to explain a given situation based on available facts and as well exposes the reader to a wealth of information and ideas on a particular topic.",
    options: ["argumentative", "descriptive", "narrative", "expository"],
    answer: "expository",
  },
  {
    question:
      "While the security operatives were sleeping, the robbers entered into their apartment and carted away their belongings is an example of---------------- sentence.",
    options: ["Compound-complex", "complex", "compound", "multiple"],
    answer: "Compound-complex",
  },
  {
    question: "There are ------------ stages in essay writing.",
    options: ["two", "three", "four", "five"],
    answer: "three",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the punctuation marks is needed in this sentence: They are brilliant aren't they?",
    options: ["The colon", "The semi-colon", "Exclamation mark", "The comma"],
    answer: "The comma",
  },
  {
    question: "According to the passage, popularize can be replaced with__",
    options: ["Publish", "teach", "undermine", "plagiarize"],
    answer: "Publish",
  },
  {
    question: "Agony as underlined above can be replaced with _____",
    options: ["distress", "humiliation", "exaltation", "anger"],
    answer: "distress",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the passage, which problem is general to both lecturers and students?",
    options: [
      "Inadequate journals",
      "inadequate funds",
      "inadequate lecture halls",
      "ill-equipped libraries",
    ],
    answer: "inadequate lecture halls",
  },
  {
    question: "These, as used in the passage is a  ______ pronoun.",
    options: ["Interrogative", "descriptive", "demonstrative", "reflexive"],
    answer: "demonstrative",
  },
  {
    question: "Beyond the students' means'. The underlined is _______",
    options: [
      "descriptive noun",
      "possessive noun",
      "modifying noun",
      "abstract noun",
    ],
    answer: "possessive noun",
  },
  {
    question: "Nigerian parliament is an example of ………..",
    options: [
      "Pronominal adjectives",
      "Proper adjectives",
      "Demonstratives adjectives",
      "Relative adjectives",
    ],
    answer: "Proper adjectives",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The kingdom of God is at hand 'The ' in this sentence is an example of ……..",
    options: [
      "Definite article",
      "Indefinite article",
      "Infinite article",
      "Finite article",
    ],
    answer: "Definite article",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Mrs. Aje doesn't know yet, but she's got two strings to her bow. She can still appeal to the chairman.",
    options: [
      "Mrs. Aje has more than one means to achieve her objective.",
      "Mrs. Aje has a strong motivation to achieve her objective.",
      "Mrs. Aje has two ideas.",
      "Mrs. Aje can shoot two strings from her bow.",
    ],
    answer: "Mrs. Aje has more than one means to achieve her objective.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "I want to go on record in favour of the President Buhari's re-election.",
    options: [
      "state emphatically",
      "embrace a position publicly",
      "write this down",
      "get a record for this purpose",
    ],
    answer: "embrace a position publicly",
  },
  {
    question: "His visits to his home town are few and far between.",
    options: ["very infrequent", "very often", "quite often", "very frequent"],
    answer: "very infrequent",
  },
  {
    question: "The children saw a dog-eared book on their father's table.",
    options: [
      "The book is worn and well-thumbed",
      "The book is about dogs",
      "The pages of the book have been eaten by dogs",
      "The pages of the book look like a dog's ear",
    ],
    answer: "The book is worn and well-thumbed",
  },
  {
    question: "The two runners finished the race in a dead heat.",
    options: [
      "together",
      "at the same time",
      "in serious pace",
      "serious anger",
    ],
    answer: "at the same time",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Once the criminal got out of prison, he swore he would go straight.",
    options: [
      "go home straight",
      "be mendacious",
      "be law-abiding",
      "be crooked",
    ],
    answer: "be law-abiding",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It was an excellent party. The only fly in the ointment was Adewale spilling red wine over the host's new carpet.",
    options: ["minor incident", "cause for concern", "issue", "problem"],
    answer: "minor incident",
  },
  {
    question: "Mary is all at sea about getting married.",
    options: [
      "Mary is confused",
      "Mary's husband lives by the sea",
      "Mary will get married by the side of the sea",
      "Mary is happy",
    ],
    answer: "Mary is confused",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Shade is always at sixes and sevens when she is home by herself.",
    options: [
      "Shade likes six and seven",
      "Shade is always well-behaved",
      "Shade is always disorderly",
      "Shade likes counting",
    ],
    answer: "Shade is always disorderly",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If Dayo would not act high and mighty, he would have many friends.",
    options: [
      "Dayo is tall",
      "Dayo acts proud and powerful",
      "Dayo wants people to think he is proud and powerful",
      "Dayo thinks he is proud and powerful",
    ],
    answer: "Dayo acts proud and powerful",
  },
  {
    question: "I hope that the facts will bear out your story.",
    options: [
      "prove that you are right",
      "prove that you have a story to tell",
      "prove that you have a wonderful story",
      "prove that bears and stories go together",
    ],
    answer: "prove that you are right",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The pedestrians have to walk cheek by jowl along the narrow streets.",
    options: [
      "walk in discomfort",
      "walk closely together",
      "walk apart",
      "walk with jaws clenched",
    ],
    answer: "walk closely together",
  },
  {
    question: "A poor listener only____",
    options: [
      "listen for facts",
      "listen to the concluding statements",
      "listen to the introductory remarks",
      "bothers about the speaker's language",
    ],
    answer: "listen for facts",
  },
  {
    question: "An outline helps the student to___",
    options: [
      "memorize points",
      "date his/her materials",
      "structure his/her assignment",
      "summarize his/her work",
    ],
    answer: "structure his/her assignment",
  },
  {
    question: "A good student must provide___ for his/her work",
    options: [
      "only the page of source material",
      "only the publishers of the source material",
      "the initials of the author referred to",
      "a reference for his/her work",
    ],
    answer: "a reference for his/her work",
  },
  {
    question: "Plagiarism does not cover____",
    options: [
      "copying from other person's work",
      "information that is common knowledge",
      "lifting other peoples ideas mindlessly",
      "a reference for his/her work",
    ],
    answer: "information that is common knowledge",
  },
  {
    question: "A good learner____",
    options: [
      "goes to the library everyday",
      "is an attentive listener",
      "sits always in front of the class",
      "always asks questions in class",
    ],
    answer: "is an attentive listener",
  },
  {
    question: "One of these is a more rigorous way of getting knowledge___",
    options: ["reading", "studying", "acting", "talking"],
    answer: "studying",
  },
  {
    question: "Unlike communication, language is____",
    options: [
      "human specific",
      "animal specific",
      "human and animal specific",
      "neither animal nor human specific",
    ],
    answer: "human specific",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When a language lacks a logical connection between words or sounds and the objects it refers to, it is said to be___",
    options: ["arbitrary", "objective", "subjective", "unintelligible"],
    answer: "arbitrary",
  },
  {
    question: "____ occurs when a language is used to talk about language",
    options: ["semanticity", "discreteness", "creativity", "reflexibility"],
    answer: "reflexibility",
  },
  {
    question: "Anything that reduces the fidelity of communication is____",
    options: ["noise", "medium", "feedback", "stimulus"],
    answer: "noise",
  },
  {
    question: "Body movement is a form of___",
    options: ["proxemics", "kinesics", "chronemics", "distance"],
    answer: "kinesics",
  },
  {
    question: "Horizontal communication takes place___",
    options: [
      "during lectures",
      "among people of the same rank",
      "between a boss and a worker",
      "between father and son",
    ],
    answer: "among people of the same rank",
  },
  {
    question: "Communication has_____ essential components",
    options: ["six", "nine", "eight", "twelve"],
    answer: "eight",
  },
  {
    question: "____ is a proper noun",
    options: ["Ada", "knowledge", "casts", "markets"],
    answer: "Ada",
  },
  {
    question: "There are six ___ in the garden",
    options: ["ox", "oxen", "oxs", "oxes"],
    answer: "oxen",
  },
  {
    question: "He blamed himself. “himself” in this sentence is___",
    options: [
      "reflexive pronoun",
      "interrogative pronoun",
      "intensive pronoun",
      "reciprocal pronoun",
    ],
    answer: "reflexive pronoun",
  },
  {
    question: "One of the following shows an adverb of manner",
    options: [
      "They lived happily",
      "He has gone there",
      "She went to Lagos yesterday",
      "She will come",
    ],
    answer: "They lived happily",
  },
  {
    question: "“he loves reading” is an example of___",
    options: [
      "simple present tense",
      "past present tense",
      "present perfect tense",
      "past continuous tense",
    ],
    answer: "simple present tense",
  },
  {
    question: "She congratulated him___ his success at the polls",
    options: ["for", "at", "on", "in"],
    answer: "on",
  },
  {
    question: "“Do not go there” is an___ sentence",
    options: ["declarative", "imperative", "optative", "exclamatory"],
    answer: "imperative",
  },
  {
    question: "The rich should help the poor. The underlined is the____",
    options: ["predicate", "subject", "complex sentence", "subordinate clause"],
    answer: "subject",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Change the sentence, Paul said, “Brother, I am coming” to Indirect Speech",
    options: [
      "Paul said that he was coming",
      "Paul says I am coming",
      "Paul said that I am coming",
      "“I am coming”, says Paul.",
    ],
    answer: "Paul said that he was coming",
  },
  {
    question:
      "“He told me that he was hungry” changed to Direct Speech it becomes___",
    options: [
      "Peter said, “I am hungry”",
      "Peter says he was hungry",
      "I am hungry says Peter",
      "I was hungry said Peter",
    ],
    answer: "Peter said, “I am hungry”",
  },
  {
    question: "Yesterday, Tunde asked Charles___",
    options: [
      "if he was tired",
      "if he is tired",
      "whether he was tired",
      "whether he is tired",
    ],
    answer: "if he was tired",
  },
  {
    question: "Tolu asked Shade ___",
    options: [
      "what her plan was",
      "what her plan is",
      "what is his plan",
      "what was her plan",
    ],
    answer: "what her plan was",
  },
  {
    question: "He told them___",
    options: [
      "hurry up",
      "to have hurry up",
      "to be hurried up",
      "to hurry up",
    ],
    answer: "to hurry up",
  },
  {
    question: "They said that____",
    options: [
      "she will come",
      "she would come",
      "is going to come",
      "she may come",
    ],
    answer: "she would come",
  },
  {
    question: "The Vice Chancellor asked me___",
    options: [
      "what is my name",
      "what was my name",
      "what my name was",
      "what my name should be",
    ],
    answer: "what my name was",
  },
  {
    question: "Ade is a greenhorn. This means that Ade is___",
    options: ["inexperienced", "not tall", "fair-skinned", "hardworker"],
    answer: "inexperienced",
  },
  {
    question: "He told him to go on___ till six p.m.",
    options: ["working", "worked", "works", "to work"],
    answer: "working",
  },
  {
    question: "She acts ___ she is the Vice-Chancellor",
    options: ["as if", "if she", "that", "as"],
    answer: "as if",
  },
  {
    question: "Must you greet everybody every day, No, I___",
    options: ["can't", "mustn't", "shouldn't", "should"],
    answer: "mustn't",
  },
  {
    question: "When one is immune to an illness, one is____",
    options: [
      "opposed to it",
      "attached to it",
      "protected against it",
      "addicted to it",
    ],
    answer: "protected against it",
  },
  {
    question: "You should make an___ to improve the situation",
    options: ["effect", "effort", "efficiency", "effectiveness"],
    answer: "effort",
  },
  {
    question: "It is difficult these days to get a seat___ the plane",
    options: ["inside", "in", "on", "into"],
    answer: "on",
  },
  {
    question: "He travelled to Lagos ___ train",
    options: ["in", "on", "inside", "by"],
    answer: "by",
  },
  {
    question: "You surely want some___, don't you?",
    options: ["loaves", "loafs", "loavs", "loavses"],
    answer: "loaves",
  },
  {
    question: "She was reported___ the lecturer",
    options: [
      "to be assaulting",
      "to have assaulted",
      "to have been assaulted",
      "to assault",
    ],
    answer: "to have assaulted",
  },
  {
    question: "The girl who won the prize was my___",
    options: ["friend", "a friend of mine", "the friend", "my own friend"],
    answer: "friend",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If you give me what I want, I will be happy. Here, 'what I want' is___",
    options: [
      "an adjective clause",
      "an adverbial clause",
      "a noun clause",
      "an infinitive clause",
    ],
    answer: "a noun clause",
  },
  {
    question: "That boy in your class sings well, This is an example of___",
    options: [
      "simple sentence",
      "compound sentence",
      "complex sentence",
      "compound-complex sentence",
    ],
    answer: "complex sentence",
  },
  {
    question:
      "He studied hard to pass his examination. The sentence above shows___",
    options: [
      "a conditional clause",
      "an adverbial clause",
      "a relative clause",
      "an infinitive clause",
    ],
    answer: "an adverbial clause",
  },
  {
    question: "The books on the shelf is ___",
    options: ["moved", "moving", "mover", "moves"],
    answer: "moved",
  },
  {
    question: "The children and their mother ___ happy",
    options: ["is", "was", "were", "are"],
    answer: "are",
  },
  {
    question:
      "He doesn't have money; he spends all he earns. The second part is___",
    options: [
      "an independent clause",
      "a compound clause",
      "a subordinate clause",
      "a dependent clause",
    ],
    answer: "an independent clause",
  },
  {
    question: "I think she may be coming. 'May be' in this sentence is___",
    options: [
      "a modal verb",
      "a phrasal verb",
      "an auxiliary verb",
      "a gerund",
    ],
    answer: "a modal verb",
  },
  {
    question: "My sister, the nurse, lives in Lagos. This is an example of___",
    options: [
      "a compound sentence",
      "a simple sentence",
      "a complex sentence",
      "an elliptical sentence",
    ],
    answer: "a complex sentence",
  },
  {
    question: "He says he will be back___ a few minutes",
    options: ["after", "in", "within", "before"],
    answer: "in",
  },
  {
    question: "When we meet again, I will tell you___",
    options: [
      "what I did",
      "what I had done",
      "what have I done",
      "what I have done",
    ],
    answer: "what I did",
  },
  {
    question: "I often think of the past___",
    options: ["after", "beyond", "behind", "past"],
    answer: "behind",
  },
  {
    question: "She swims as___ as a fish",
    options: ["quickly", "fast", "swiftly", "speedily"],
    answer: "fast",
  },
  {
    question: "What time do you usually wake ___?",
    options: ["of", "up", "in", "out"],
    answer: "up",
  },
  {
    question: "Do you know when she will be___?",
    options: ["back", "return", "come back", "come"],
    answer: "back",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Which of these is not one of the factors that aid students' listening skill?",
    options: [
      "identify the defining moments of the lecture",
      "encourage distractions",
      "avoid negative influence",
      "concentrate on the message",
    ],
    answer: "encourage distractions",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of these is not one of the tips for developing efficient study habits",
    options: [
      "streamline your notes",
      "schedule your time",
      "attend class occasionally",
      "minimize distractions",
    ],
    answer: "attend class occasionally",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All the points below except one will enable students to deliver on their assignment __",
    options: [
      "plan",
      "ignore relevant information about the assignment",
      "analyse the question",
      "edit and proofread",
    ],
    answer: "ignore relevant information about the assignment",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ is the act of appropriating intellectual material of other people for use without proper acknowledgement",
    options: ["forgery", "fraud", "plagiarism", "impersonation"],
    answer: "plagiarism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Students can avoid plagiarism through all the following except___",
    options: [
      "cite the works consulted",
      "paraphrase ideas",
      "reference the materials used",
      "quote from other sources without acknowledgement",
    ],
    answer: "quote from other sources without acknowledgement",
  },
  {
    question: "By saying that “language is human specific”, it means that:",
    options: [
      "only human beings communicate",
      "only human beings use language",
      "all living things use language",
      "language only exists in the spoken form",
    ],
    answer: "only human beings use language",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Language is defined as “a purely human and non-instinctive method of communicating ideas, emotions and desires by means of a system of voluntarily produced symbols” by___",
    options: ["Sapir", "Womack", "Osisanwo", "Tamunobelema"],
    answer: "Sapir",
  },
  {
    question: "Language is found____",
    options: [
      "wherever there are problems",
      "among the primitive people only",
      "among only the civilized people",
      "wherever human beings exist",
    ],
    answer: "wherever human beings exist",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these is not true about language?",
    options: [
      "it is creative",
      "it is rule governed",
      "it is both spoken and written",
      "it is instinctive",
    ],
    answer: "it is instinctive",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The feature of language which refers to lack of logical connection between words or sounds and the objects they refer to is___",
    options: [
      "productivity",
      "arbitrariness",
      "transferability",
      "semanticity",
    ],
    answer: "arbitrariness",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The characteristics of language that makes it possible for human beings to discuss things that are not immediately available is___",
    options: ["vocal-auditory", "performative", "displacement", "openness"],
    answer: "displacement",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Pick from the options below the one that is not among the features of language____",
    options: [
      "reflexibility",
      "rule governance",
      "creativity",
      "instinctiveness",
    ],
    answer: "instinctiveness",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The role of language that makes it possible for human beings to establish and maintain social relationship among human beings is_____",
    options: [
      "informative role",
      "phatic role",
      "performative role",
      "documentation role",
    ],
    answer: "phatic role",
  },
  {
    question: "___is the element that triggers communication process",
    options: ["stimulus", "grammaticality", "intention", "encoder"],
    answer: "stimulus",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ is “normally regarded as the core component of the communication process”",
    options: ["stimulus", "encoder", "proxemics", "message"],
    answer: "message",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Encoder in communication process is also called all the following except_____",
    options: ["transmitter", "sender", "source", "director"],
    answer: "director",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of these is not a type of noise in communication process?____",
    options: ["linguistic", "kinesics", "grammatical", "channel"],
    answer: "channel",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A decoder as an element of communication is also called all the following except___",
    options: ["the receiver", "the hearer", "the audience", "the feedback"],
    answer: "the feedback",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____is the means through which the message is transmitted to the receiver",
    options: ["medium", "channel", "speaking", "audio"],
    answer: "channel",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of these is not part of the oral medium through which a message can be sent in the process of communication?___",
    options: ["radio", "telephone", "face-to-face", "poster"],
    answer: "poster",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____is the best if immediate feedback is needed in communication process",
    options: [
      "written communication",
      "oral communication",
      "non-verbal",
      "icons",
    ],
    answer: "oral communication",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The written medium through which a message can be sent during communication can be all the following except___",
    options: ["tracts", "reports", "memo", "carving"],
    answer: "carving",
  },
  {
    question: "____ represents the receiver's reaction to the message sent.",
    options: ["feedback", "stimulus", "idea", "chronemics"],
    answer: "feedback",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ involves the use of the spoken form of the language to pass across information to the decoder",
    options: [
      "written communication",
      "oral communication",
      "non-verbal communication",
      "signing",
    ],
    answer: "oral communication",
  },
  {
    question: "All the following are examples of kinesics except______",
    options: ["postures", "illustrators", "regulators", "appearance"],
    answer: "appearance",
  },
  {
    question: "____refers to how time is used to communicate",
    options: ["hoptics", "chronemics", "iconics", "affect displays"],
    answer: "chronemics",
  },
  {
    question: "“Monday” is an example of___ noun",
    options: ["collective", "common", "proper", "abstract"],
    answer: "proper",
  },
  {
    question: "“Happy” is an example of what part of speech?__",
    options: ["adjective", "noun", "adverb", "preposition"],
    answer: "adjective",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these does not belong to the group?",
    options: ["adjectives", "conjunctions", "verbs", "sentence"],
    answer: "sentence",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these is not an example of abstract noun?",
    options: ["freedom", "justice", "house", "truth"],
    answer: "house",
  },
  {
    question: "Uncountable nouns combine with all the following except_____",
    options: ["much", "some", "little", "many"],
    answer: "many",
  },
  {
    question: "The plural form of “proof” is_____",
    options: ["proves", "prooves", "proofs", "proved"],
    answer: "proofs",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All the following are nouns which end in “s” but are singular in meaning except____",
    options: ["phonetics", "news", "boys", "economics"],
    answer: "boys",
  },
  {
    question: "“Mice” is the plural form of ____",
    options: ["mix", "mouse", "miss", "mince"],
    answer: "mouse",
  },
  {
    question: "All the following are examples of masculine gender except___",
    options: ["father", "monk", "bitch", "wizard"],
    answer: "bitch",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the options below is not correct?",
    options: ["deer", "oxen", "equipments", "men-servants"],
    answer: "equipments",
  },
  {
    question: "All the following are the roles of a noun except____",
    options: [
      "it can function as a subject",
      "it can function as a modifier",
      "it can function as an object",
      "it can function as a conjunction",
    ],
    answer: "it can function as a conjunction",
  },
  {
    question: "The grammatical function of a noun in a sentence is____",
    options: [
      "to denote action",
      "to identify a person, place, thing or idea",
      "to make the sentence cohesive",
      "to add adjectives to the sentence",
    ],
    answer: "to identify a person, place, thing or idea",
  },
  {
    question: "____is the basis of the unity and coherence of a paragraph",
    options: ["topic sentence", "idea", "transition", "introduction"],
    answer: "topic sentence",
  },
  {
    question: "All the following are types of transitions except____",
    options: [
      "internal transitions",
      "external transitions",
      "symbolic transitions",
      "sequential transitions",
    ],
    answer: "symbolic transitions",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A paragraph that gives explanations about a subject matter is____",
    options: [
      "narrative paragraph",
      "descriptive paragraph",
      "expository paragraph",
      "persuasive paragraph",
    ],
    answer: "expository paragraph",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following does not belong to the group?",
    options: ["introduction", "body", "conclusion", "sentence"],
    answer: "sentence",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is not true about the body of a paragraph?",
    options: [
      "it provides details about the topic sentence",
      "it adds supporting ideas",
      "it ends the paragraph",
      "it includes examples or illustrations",
    ],
    answer: "it ends the paragraph",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following should not be included in a conclusion?",
    options: [
      "summary of points discussed",
      "revisiting of topic sentence",
      "introduction of new ideas",
      "final thoughts on the subject",
    ],
    answer: "introduction of new ideas",
  },
  {
    question: "A well-developed paragraph should include____",
    options: [
      "a topic sentence",
      "supporting details",
      "concluding sentence",
      "all of the above",
    ],
    answer: "all of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Attentive listeners not only hear, but effectively process the …………..presented to them.",
    options: ["study", "skills", "information", "forms"],
    answer: "information",
  },
  {
    question: "These are the tips for developing efficient study habits except",
    options: [
      "attend class and review course materials regularly",
      "streamline your notes",
      "schedule your time",
      "dress appearance",
    ],
    answer: "dress appearance",
  },
  {
    question: "What are the features of language?",
    options: ["creativity", "discreteness", "performance", "semanticity"],
    answer: "creativity",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The act of appropriating intellectual material of other people (in this case) academic scholars for use as if they were your own without appropriate acknowledgment is known as…………..",
    options: ["essay reports", "theses", "plagiarism", "journal articles"],
    answer: "plagiarism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Avoiding distraction during lectures will enable a student to do the following except…………………",
    options: [
      "pick salient points",
      "achieve effective note-taking",
      "referencing",
      "listen with rapt attention",
    ],
    answer: "referencing",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Five important things to know in order to avoid plagiarism are: …………",
    options: [
      "Paraphrasing, citing texts, quoting, referencing and conclusion",
      "Citing, paraphrasing, quoting, summary and plagiarism",
      "Referencing, conclusion quoting and avoiding citing",
      "Referencing, conclusion, quoting and avoiding citing",
    ],
    answer: "Referencing, conclusion, quoting and avoiding citing",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The important tool of communication among human beings is …………..",
    options: ["Concept", "Communication", "Symbols", "Language"],
    answer: "Language",
  },
  {
    question: "These are some of the features of language except………….",
    options: ["Creativity", "Displacement", "Communication", "Semanticity"],
    answer: "Displacement",
  },
  {
    question:
      "………………… refers to a situation where language is used to talk about language.",
    options: ["Discreteness", "Displacement", "Arbitrariness", "Ability"],
    answer: "Displacement",
  },
  {
    question: "Directive role in language functions are ………",
    options: [
      "Persuade, advise, order, instruct or influence other people",
      "Persuade, advise, monitor, order, instruct or influence other people",
      "Persuade, object, advise, monitor or influence other people",
      "Persuade, advise, follow, order, instruct or influence other people",
    ],
    answer: "Persuade, advise, order, instruct or influence other people",
  },
  {
    question:
      "……………..refers to the role of language in establishing and maintaining social relationship among human beings.",
    options: [
      "Phatic role",
      "Informative role",
      "Directive role",
      "Performative role",
    ],
    answer: "Phatic role",
  },
  {
    question:
      "……………..involves transmission of ideas, information, intention between two or more individuals.",
    options: ["Stimulus", "Encoder", "Communication", "Language"],
    answer: "Communication",
  },
  {
    question: "Elements of communication include the following except ………",
    options: ["Noise", "Documentation", "Message", "Stimulus"],
    answer: "Documentation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "……………… is a cover term representing all forms of obstacles or barriers that can hinder the effectiveness of communication",
    options: ["Noise", "Documentation", "Message", "Stimulus"],
    answer: "Noise",
  },
  {
    question:
      "………..is a form of communication that takes among the people of the same rank in an organization.",
    options: [
      "Vertical communication",
      "Horizontal Communication",
      "Diagonal Communication",
      "Semi-vertical Communication",
    ],
    answer: "Horizontal Communication",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Identify the common noun in this sentence: He found his key under the table.",
    options: ["found, table", "key, table", "under, the", "key, under"],
    answer: "key, table",
  },
  {
    question: "………….. refers to the names of particular person and places.",
    options: ["Noun", "proper noun", "common noun", "Abstract noun"],
    answer: "proper noun",
  },
  {
    question:
      "……… are names of qualities, action, or condition that do not possess physical existence hence cannot be founded or seen",
    options: ["Abstract noun", "Proper noun", "common noun", "concrete noun"],
    answer: "Abstract noun",
  },
  {
    question: "Myself is an example of",
    options: [
      "personal pronoun",
      "Relative pronoun",
      "Intensive pronoun",
      "Indefinite pronoun",
    ],
    answer: "Intensive pronoun",
  },
  {
    question: "Effective communication involves _________.",
    options: ["time", "feedback", "research", "speed"],
    answer: "feedback",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these is not a type of listening?",
    options: [
      "discriminative listening",
      "critical listening",
      "appreciative listening",
      "sympathetic listening",
    ],
    answer: "sympathetic listening",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The kind of discriminatory listener that retains information and also evaluates it is called _____.",
    options: [
      "retentive listener",
      "reflective listener",
      "emphatic listener",
      "reactive listener",
    ],
    answer: "reflective listener",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Clarity, vividness, concreteness and lack of clutter are all features of _________.",
    options: [
      "effective reading",
      "effective speaking",
      "appropriate wording",
      "reinforcing",
    ],
    answer: "effective speaking",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To cement the bond of trust between the speaker and the audience, one of these is not taken into consideration.",
    options: [
      "use of personal pronouns",
      "alluding to common experience",
      "use of inappropriate language",
      "building hypothetical questions",
    ],
    answer: "use of inappropriate language",
  },
  {
    question: "Most humans talk at a rate of ____ per minute.",
    options: ["130-170", "140-180", "100-180", "80-180"],
    answer: "130-170",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of these is not a principal variable of bodily action in communication.",
    options: ["listening", "gesture", "facial expression", "movement"],
    answer: "listening",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Selecting, reinforcing and initiating are important in ____________.",
    options: ["speaking", "listening", "note taking", "articulation"],
    answer: "listening",
  },
  {
    question: "As an act, listening demands ________ attention.",
    options: [
      "emotional and emphatic",
      "physical and psychological",
      "physical and physiological",
      "mental and metaphorical",
    ],
    answer: "physical and psychological",
  },
  {
    question: "The two most important linguistic activities are _______.",
    options: [
      "reading and speaking",
      "speaking and listening",
      "listening and reading",
      "reading and studying",
    ],
    answer: "speaking and listening",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In each of the questions below, choose the option nearest in meaning to the word(s) or phrase(s) underlined. Peter, can you please start the generator?",
    options: ["begin", "commence", "kick off", "put on"],
    answer: "commence",
  },
  {
    question: "It is futile trying to make bricks without straw.",
    options: ["fertile", "bad", "pointless", "easy"],
    answer: "pointless",
  },
  {
    question: "The committee condemned his lacklustre report.",
    options: ["enthusiastic", "praiseworthy", "wordy", "dull"],
    answer: "dull",
  },
  {
    question: "Mrs. Ojo regarded the experience as a timely caveat.",
    options: ["warning", "bargain", "purchase", "development"],
    answer: "warning",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Vice-Chancellor advised the new students to eschew unethical conducts.",
    options: ["develop", "escape", "prevent", "shun"],
    answer: "shun",
  },
  {
    question: "It was surprising how we took to the new lecturer at once.",
    options: [
      "talked so long with",
      "introduced ourselves to",
      "formed a liking for",
      "started fighting",
    ],
    answer: "formed a liking for",
  },
  {
    question: "Mr. Alao plays the piano with great dexterity.",
    options: ["wisdom", "skill", "power", "force"],
    answer: "skill",
  },
  {
    question: "All the accident victims are bleeding profusely.",
    options: ["slowly", "clearly", "excessively", "diffusely"],
    answer: "excessively",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Even though there is no obvious riot in the community, the atmosphere is restive.",
    options: ["quiet", "chaotic", "restless", "peaceful"],
    answer: "restless",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The clerk insisted I show her my credentials before I could be registered.",
    options: ["papers", "qualifications", "testimonials", "identities"],
    answer: "qualifications",
  },
  {
    question: "Ajayi is a die-hard criminal.",
    options: [
      "hard to kill",
      "very difficult",
      "remorseless",
      "hard to arrest",
    ],
    answer: "remorseless",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Our local paper is noted for its incisive editorials on local politics.",
    options: ["sarcastic", "decisive", "destructive", "penetrating"],
    answer: "penetrating",
  },
  {
    question: "The lawyer gave evasive answers to all the questions.",
    options: ["vague", "unintelligent", "ineffective", "unreliable"],
    answer: "vague",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Head of Department called for concerted efforts in order to get over the problems.",
    options: ["isolated", "disparate", "desperate", "combined"],
    answer: "combined",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In his quest for solidarity, the party leader undertook a state-wide tour.",
    options: ["unity", "resistance", "mobilization", "re-organisation"],
    answer: "unity",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The material in the book is presented within an eclectic framework.",
    options: ["a simple", "a restricted", "a broad", "a clumsy"],
    answer: "a broad",
  },
  {
    question: "Mary had a brainwave as to how she could deal with the problem.",
    options: ["a desire", "an idea", "a headache", "an inspiration"],
    answer: "an idea",
  },
  {
    question: "Surely, Mr. Dada is a ball of fire.",
    options: [
      "a quarrelsome person",
      "a hot-headed activist",
      "a fiery speaker or writer",
      "a very energetic person",
    ],
    answer: "a very energetic person",
  },
  {
    question: "Hers was a chequered carrier.",
    options: [
      "an interesting and successful carrier",
      "a carrier full of ups and downs",
      "a carrier full of sorrow and tears",
      "a bright and memorable carrier",
    ],
    answer: "a carrier full of ups and downs",
  },
  {
    question: "The gateman does his work perfunctorily.",
    options: ["with speed", "enthusiastically", "carelessly", "grudgingly"],
    answer: "carelessly",
  },
  {
    question: "In my view, the play didn’t come off.",
    options: ["succeed", "fail", "attract applause", "take place"],
    answer: "fail",
  },
  {
    question: "The chairman’s plans for the future are in the air.",
    options: ["suspended", "floating", "empty", "uncertain"],
    answer: "uncertain",
  },
  {
    question: "There are many venal judges in our law courts today.",
    options: ["qualified", "honest", "corrupt", "professional"],
    answer: "corrupt",
  },
  {
    question: "Many Nigerians have inured themselves to hardship.",
    options: ["accustomed", "subjected", "submitted", "endeared"],
    answer: "accustomed",
  },
  {
    question:
      "For a long time, the robber defied police warning as if he was invulnerable.",
    options: [
      "indifferent to danger",
      "impossible to harm",
      "difficult to catch",
      "perfectly justifiable",
    ],
    answer: "impossible to harm",
  },
  {
    question: "To most people last Christmas was an austere period.",
    options: ["stern", "harsh", "happy", "prosperous"],
    answer: "happy",
  },
  {
    question: "This card entitles you to attend the occasion.",
    options: ["disqualifies", "invites", "discourages", "wants"],
    answer: "invites",
  },
  {
    question: "This is an abridged version of the constitution.",
    options: ["edited", "exciting", "inexistent", "enlarged"],
    answer: "enlarged",
  },
  {
    question: "The internet is full of fallacious stories.",
    options: ["misleading", "truthful", "erroneous", "trivial"],
    answer: "misleading",
  },
  {
    question: "His father gave him a long lecture on the virtues of honesty.",
    options: ["warning", "command", "talk", "advice"],
    answer: "advice",
  },
  {
    question: "She always finds herself in the limelight.",
    options: ["publicity", "trouble", "problems", "punishment"],
    answer: "publicity",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In my discussion, I have limited myself to controversial issues.",
    options: ["disputable", "contemptible", "unarguable", "exaggerated"],
    answer: "disputable",
  },
  {
    question: "She was always behind the others because of her lethargy.",
    options: ["carelessness", "laziness", "stupidity", "timidity"],
    answer: "laziness",
  },
  {
    question: "The chairman’s arguments are tenable.",
    options: ["sensible", "weak", "offensive", "defensible"],
    answer: "defensible",
  },
  {
    question: "She turned out to be an impudent child.",
    options: ["bold", "weak", "insulting", "uncontrollable"],
    answer: "insulting",
  },
  {
    question: "Her doggedness won her the match.",
    options: ["weakness", "stubbornness", "confidence", "determination"],
    answer: "determination",
  },

  // First Comprehension section
  {
    comprehension: `
      Many University teachers are laboring in deep agony nowadays. What is the source of this agony? The first is the absence of adequate material for standard academic work. Libraries, laboratories, journals and research funds have become greatly inadequate for the scholar's own researches. These people, popularly called lecturers are first and foremost professional seekers after new knowledge with a piece of chalk like every other teacher. They teach only in order to popularize the result of their research as relevant to our day-to-day world or in order to groom new researchers to take their places.
      This brings us to the second cause of agony. This is the departure of job satisfaction in general. Lecture halls for the lecturers and students are grossly inadequate, textbooks are beyond the students' means; journals are unavailable for his more advanced students. Hardly can students buy paper for notes and handouts. The departments are so depleted that the lecturer is overstretched and the result of collective effort is impoverished.
      (Culled from Adeyanju and Egwuogu 2011: 96-97, 3rd Edition)`,

    instruction: "Read the passage below and answer the questions:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "According to the passage, 'popularize' can be replaced with:",
        options: ["publish", "teach", "undermine", "plagiarize"],
        answer: "publish",
      },
      {
        question: "Agony as underlined in the passage can be replaced with:",
        options: ["distress", "humiliation", "exaltation", "anger"],
        answer: "distress",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the passage, which problem is general to both lecturers and students?",
        options: [
          "Inadequate journals",
          "inadequate funds",
          "inadequate lecture halls",
          "ill equipped libraries",
        ],
        answer: "inadequate lecture halls",
      },
      {
        question: "'These' as used in the passage is a ______ pronoun.",
        options: ["Interrogative", "descriptive", "demonstrative", "reflexive"],
        answer: "demonstrative",
      },
      {
        question: "Beyond the students' means. The underlined is a ______.",
        options: [
          "descriptive noun",
          "possessive noun",
          "modifying noun",
          "abstract noun",
        ],
        answer: "possessive noun",
      },
    ],
  },

  // Second Comprehension section
  {
    comprehension: `
      The heart attack is a serious medical condition in which the heart stops working normally. The oxygen supply to some parts of the heart is restricted so severely that heart cells die. The usual cause is a coronary thrombosis, that is a blocking of the flow of blood by a blood clot in an artery supplying blood to the heart. In about four-fifths of heart attacks, the victim suffers pain in the chest or upper abdomen, often associated with nausea, sweating and indigestion, producing belching. The pain is often described as 'crushing' or squeezing' and may spread to the neck, jaw or arms. Anxiety and palpitation often accompany it. Shortness of breath may be a further symptom, or on rare occasions, the only symptom occurring.
      There is a 50 percent chance that a heart attack will so badly interrupt the flow of oxygenated blood to the body that it ends in death.`,
    instruction: "Read the passage below and answer the questions:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "According to the passage, during a heart attack:",
        options: [
          "the heart works perfectly",
          "the heart stops working immediately",
          "the heart functions abnormally",
          "the heart dies",
        ],
        answer: "the heart functions abnormally",
      },
      {
        question: "Heart attack takes place when:",
        options: [
          "there is an unrestricted free flow of blood to the heart",
          "the artery carrying blood to the heart is ruptured",
          "there is a blockage of blood flow to the heart due to a blood clot",
          "the victim does not exercise regularly",
        ],
        answer:
          "there is a blockage of blood flow to the heart due to a blood clot",
      },
      {
        question: "From the passage, it is clear that heart attack is:",
        options: [
          "a mild medical condition",
          "a grave medical condition",
          "an unknown medical condition",
          "a tropical medical condition",
        ],
        answer: "a grave medical condition",
      },
      {
        question: "The word 'palpitation' means:",
        options: [
          "rapid or strong heartbeats",
          "shortness of breath",
          "belching",
          "fainting",
        ],
        answer: "rapid or strong heartbeats",
      },
      {
        question: "The word 'indigestion' refers to:",
        options: [
          "pain in the upper abdomen",
          "squeezing pain in the chest",
          "lack of oxygen to the heart",
          "nausea",
        ],
        answer: "pain in the upper abdomen",
      },
    ],
  },

  // Third Comprehension section
  {
    comprehension: `
      Though assumption is the lowest level of knowledge; it is still a form of knowledge, and knowledge is key. Assumptions are the foundation upon which interpretation and conclusion are built. Everything in life operates under certain assumptions.
      We make management decisions based on the assumptions we hold about how management ought to function and how people ought to be governed. For some of us, we consciously imbibe assumptions and principles about life and consciously decide based on them; for others, it is unconsciously but potent all the same. Our assumptions will either drown us or help us soar through life.
      We have always seen life as an immense mansion with many rooms. Some rooms lead to wealth, others to the opposite. Ultimately, we decide where we end up; and life, thus far, has proved that not everyone of us decides well, we all behave differently where we have different levels of understanding, and behave the way where our understanding is the same. We eat because we all understand the consequences of not eating. We all wear clothes because each of us comprehends lunacy. The list goes on and on. It is inevitable that some of us will make choices that get and keep us on the lower rung of the ladder by reason of exposure, training or some other variables. Life is about role-playing. We choose our role wisely or foolishly, consciously or unconsciously. Some of us get wiser to new levels of self-awareness enough to redefine our role, while others make no effort to build further capacity and therefore remain where they are. It is based on those realities that we draw the conclusion that not everyone will be wealthy in life. We lead, inspire and motivate people to strive and succeed. It is also important that we paint the full and true picture of life so that we can discourage vain pursuit. Balance must be enthroned as a critical component of truth, and people know, for instance, that 'the top' is not a place that all must ascend.
      Our greatest consolation lies in our deep conviction that true prosperity is in fulfillment through hard work than in intangible acquisition. There are set roles that some of us have been wired up to play in life but which we are not content enough to play because society esteems such roles to be inferior. Take the almost sacred office of a teacher for instance; there are people who have the natural gifts and inclinations to be school teachers. But the teaching profession, as it is, does not appear to be lucrative. So we have people who could have been more fulfilled and effective working as school teachers serving in banks.
    `,
    instruction: "Read the passage below and answer the following questions:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "According to the writer, people lead and motivate others because they want to",
        options: [
          "project individual contribution",
          "encourage selfless service",
          "make the world a home",
          "prevent empty search",
        ],
        answer: "prevent empty search",
      },
      {
        question:
          "According to the passage, balance must be enthroned because it is",
        options: [
          "a critical interdependent function",
          "an amazing help for conscience",
          "a critical part of fidelity",
          "a serious way of ensuring success",
        ],
        answer: "a critical interdependent function",
      },
      {
        question: "The word inclinations, as in the passage means",
        options: ["creeds", "tendencies", "inhibitions", "power"],
        answer: "tendencies",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following statements is true according to the passage?",
        options: [
          "greatness in life emerges when square pegs are put in round holes",
          "people do certain things in life because they know the repercussion",
          "people agree on all issues and behave the same way for the same reason",
          "understanding life at different levels gives no account of visible acquisition",
        ],
        answer:
          "people do certain things in life because they know the repercussion",
      },
      {
        question: "From the passage, it can be inferred that",
        options: [
          "people insincerely discuss facts that govern their behavior",
          "all managerial decisions are based on assumptions",
          "people make conscious efforts to acquire hidden knowledge",
          "all things in life exist on some beliefs",
        ],
        answer: "all things in life exist on some beliefs",
      },
    ],
  },
];
